SERGEY EREMEEV

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Sokolova-Sokolenka str, 8/78, Vladimir, 600018, Russia T: +7 (904) 859 87 42 | E: 13.eremeev.sv@gmail.com

Personal Statement

Many developers can display years of experience behind their backs, a decent portfolio and a knowledge about various technologies. However, most developers lack one thing - discipline. There is nothing more important than being able to sit down and work when you do not feel like it, to get inspired when you feel sick, to think critically when you are tired, to keep learning when you want to rest. Discipline turns a talented person into the exceptional one. The lack of it just makes him average. The only way to achieve success is constant self-improvement and the only valid point of reference is you the day earlier.

Having a person in a team who truly values discipline is the best way to achieve greater results and help others transform their approach to daily tasks. You shall never worry about deadlines, missed opportunities, weak work standards and other potentially harming factors because they simply do not exist in the life of a truly disciplined individual. I am not scared of being put out of my comfort zone, I enjoy tight deadlines because I see challenge in them, I love harder problems because they give meaning to my work, and I want more responsibilities because I can not wait to make an impact. I believe in the things I say. I am not afraid of promising big, because I know that I can and I will deliver even bigger.

Work Experience

The Recon Group Inc

Front-end developer

August 2014 – Present

Working in a fast-paced environment within a medium-sized team of developers on various large-scale e-commerce projects.

Duties

- Analyzing designs and making sure they fit into the selected technology
- Implementing designs using various CSS and JS frameworks
- Creating HTML email templates using various email frameworks
- Maintaining websites with an issue-tracking system (JIRA)
- Testing websites in various browsers and on different devices and ensuring full responsiveness and cross-browser compliance
- Regularly pushing updates through Git version control
- Creating WordPress websites from scratch
- Achieving faster developing environment via task runners (Grunt, Gulp, WebPack)
- Researching back-end frameworks and technologies to have a working knowledge for the entire project
- Participation in daily meet-ups, updating the team on the progress and ensuring a better planning for the future tasks
- Participating in the decision process and choosing optimal technologies

Freelancing (oDesk, Elance)

Front-end and WordPress developer

July 2011 – August 2014

Working as a freelancer you have to possess excellent communication, time-management and self-discipline skills to not only find the right client and be selected amongst hundreds of other applicants but to also be able to build a rich portfolio and make customers happy, resulting in great reviews and potential long-term relationships.

Academic Qualifications

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree – **Udacity** - 2016 Online Front-end courses – **Code School** – 2011 - 2013

Civil Engineering – University of Bath – 2010 - 2014 – Beng (Hons)

A-Levels: A*A*A*A (Double Mathematics, Phylosophy and Ethics, Politics)

Key Skills

Professional

- Proficiency in HTML, CSS, pre and postprocessors, JavaScript, JS frameworks (React, Backbone, Knockout, etc), task runners (gulp, grunt, webpack) and Git
- Ability and willingness to write clean and efficient code following the best practices
- Working knowledge of PhotoShop, Linux terminal, back-end, and SQL databases
- Good working knowledge and vast experience working with WordPress
- Experience in writing Object Oriented code and working in a Test-driven environment
- Beginner to intermediate knowledge of Ruby, Python and PHP languages
- Knowledge and continuous improvement of the algorithmic coding

Personal

- Ability to clearly communicate ideas and express thoughts in fluent English
- Excellent time-management
- Desire to face and overcome harder challenges and expand my knowledge
- Ability to stay positive and think critically under heavy pressure
- Hight attention to detail, strong creativity
- High efficiency in individual and team work
- Never copy-paste the solution, but rather understand where it came from

Hobbies & Interests

- Discovering new technologies (IoT, AI, Blockchain, etc)
- Recording, playing and enjoying music
- Making charities more accessible and easier to use to a wider public
- · Reading, reading, and more reading